David (Weibin) Ma

Toronto, ON L7B 0A5 | Phone: 647-640-6630 | Email: davidm989@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/david-weibin-ma | GitHub: https://github.com/davidma-cpu Portfolio: https://davidweibinma.ca

Summary

Energetic and enthusiastic full stack developer with experience working in agile environments, RESTful API development, HTML/CSS/JavaScript/ReactJS front-end development and building Node.js back-end systems. Strong verbal/presentation skills with ability to work independently and within teams. Great with problem-solving and passionate about designing and building modern web solutions and applications.

Professional Experience

Can United Consulting | North York, ON | Feb 2019 - Present

Web Developer

- Designing and developing company website using jQuery and BootStrap
- Maintain backend code in PHP and hosting on AWS
- Write unit tests and perform peer code reviews

OpenText | Waterloo, ON | Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

IT Service Desk Analyst

- Received employee questions via phone, instant messaging, email and ticketing system
- Procurement, setup & configuration and disposal of equipment

Fetchopia Inc. | St. Catharines, ON | Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

Junior Python Developer

- Refactored legacy code and used test driven development to debug existing code base
- Wrote a complete Python web crawler to scrape all sections of betterbidding.com and designed database schema in PostgreSQL

Sample Projects

Recipe Website | https://vast-cliffs-50637.herokuapp.com/

- Developed single page application to receive hands-free recipe recommendations and step-by-step cooking instructions from allrecipes.com
- Tools used: axios, dotenv, express, mongoose, react, react-router-dom, Google Cloud Text-to-Speech & Speech-to-Text API

News Aggregator Website | https://infinite-mesa-86642.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack web app that aggregates web content from sports and entertainment feeds to one convenient location and integrates NoSQL backend
- Tools used: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, JSON

Education

University of Toronto | Jan - July 2019

School of Continuing Studies Coding Boot Camp

Wilfrid Laurier University, Waterloo ON | June 2018

Business Administration (BBA) and Computer Science (BSc) Double Degree